the ultimate goal of trading and
investing is to make money and in order
to do that you need to understand the
trend of the market where is the market
headed so we buy or sell at the right
time and there are two ways to break
down the direction of where the market
is going to be headed the first is going
to be technical analysis and the second
is fundamental analysis so the first one
is technical analysis and the majority
of the people know it as these charts
that everybody thinks that it's Chinese
at their first look at it this is also
known as technical analysis because
you're reading price action and price
movement in real time and the second one
is through fundamental analysis and this
you identify the trend of the market by
reading news reading reports of
companies looking through the economic
reports and just read a lot of news to
really anticipate where the market is
going to be headed in this video I'm
going to focus on the fundamental
analysis just to bring wisdom and
knowledge to what this actually topic is
and what it consists of to trade
fundamental analysis I'm going to
explain to you how the fundamental
analysis works how you can use it for
your trading how you can use it to trade
your Forex fairs and exactly where to
find these news so you don't waste hours
and hours of reading articles that are
just going to give you the same thing as
one website and summarize it all as a
whole so some of you may be asking why
does the news have the power to change
the direction of the market and they
have this power because it's the
information that allows the people to
understand the real facts and the
objectives of what is actually happening
in the markets for example let's say the
Federal Reserve decides to raise
interest rates we can conclude that the
economy is not good in that very moment
because of the expansion or the credit
stimulus and the price of the money will
increase precisely by increasing
interest rates fewer people will be able
to access Credit because it will be much
more expensive to pay back these credit
cards as the debth for the economy will
be discouraged so in turn this reduces
the spending by companies and Ordinary
People in the real day-to-day econ
economy and this directly affects
companies for two reasons because they
will no longer have access to the loans
as easily as before and they will no
longer be able to get into good depth to
pay off their goods and because people
will no longer have as much money to
spend causing companies not to have the
same income this may generate losses at
the end of the month all this causes a
drop in the price of companies and the
consumer tour sectors and many many more
things and this is a very brief example
of how the outome of the news can affect
the price of a financial asset obviously
this is somewhat of an in-depth analysis
and interpretation that allows us to
understand what will happen in the
future however there's a very important
question you may be asking at this point
and that is why are these Market
movements generated by news and my
answer is very simple all the
participants Traders or people around
the world they get access to the same
information and know what is going to
happen and how it's going to impact the
price and the information and at this
point I want to make a very clear
clarification order to generate money
trading news or economics it takes an
extreme Advanced knowledge in economics
finance and all the department sector of
the businesses that run the world
because what we're doing is measuring
the impact that certain Financial events
will have on a financial asset such as
companies countries and their currencies
indices Commodities and many many many
other things and all of this requires
extreme theoretical and understanding of
the numbers of these companies and
another very clear example of
fundamental analysis is when company
reports come out all companies listed
for example on the New York Stock
Exchange or the NASDAQ are required to
report the results from time to time in
this report companies disclose or reveal
their information and their performance
and just for an example they reveal
their balance sheet their General
business and their road maps that
they're going to have from time to time
this is the balance sheet that investors
will be able to look at and anticipate
pay if it is a good idea to buy their
stock or then sell their actions but
again this is something that requires
extreme amount of advanced knowledge
with economics accounting business to be
able to anticipate what the price will
be and how it will affect the trend of
the market for example let me show you
in this very particular case how it
happened with the Federal Reserve this
is Forex Factor this is where you can
find a very summarized uh explanation of
what is going to happen in the upcoming
weeks with the news in the calendar it
shows you the different type of folders
in the market news it shows you red
folder orange yellow gray folders the
red is the stronger news the Orange is
the less stronger and obviously the
colors go down so you can filter the
news based off of these colors and this
way you can anticipate when there's
going to be certain news that are going
to come out at a specific date at a
specific time with a specific currency
pair or commodity so this is very good
to know if you're going to be trading
that commodity at that time and that
very specific date so for this example
you can see here how how the Federal
Reserve came out with news and how it
affected the price in real time you're
seeing it right here how the news
affected the movement of price but also
just temporarily and one very important
thing to keep in mind is that the
fundamentals are going to be here
forever because they just come out every
single day and they're part of the
economics of the world and these things
directly impact price and they affect of
how volatile the market is versus not in
my particular case I pay absolutely no
attention to the news I have realized
over time time that the technicals will
follow what the news will anticipate I
can anticipate if the news are going to
be bad or if they're going to be good
for a currency per based off of the
technical analysis but if you're a new
Trader out there and you want to keep in
mind of where the analysis are going to
be for the fundamentals and know when
they're going to come out when what's
the strength and at what time make sure
you check out Forex Factory Forex
Factory is where every single Trader
checks it out because it's a very
summarized way on how to see the
fundamentals of trading and it saves a
lot of time but I personally don't use
fundamentals at all and I'm generating
figures like these these or even these
simply by just looking at technical
analysis and looking at Price action and
it is 10 times easier than knowing
economics business finance and all these
different business sectors that take
years to master so my approach to the
market is far more simple and I strongly
believe far more effective because I'm
able to get more of a day-to-day trade
or more of a week- toe trade versus
fundamentals you're kind of waiting on a
corly payout of these big businesses and
these big corporations to have the big
Market swing so this is more of a
position type of trading when you're
trading with fundamentals to my
knowledge I know there's very expert
Traders out there that use it on a
day-to-day but they also Implement
technical analysis to be able to enter
their trades this is why I strictly
remove the fundamental sector of my
trading and I only focus on technical
analysis this way keeps my trading far
more simple and far more effective so if
you want to know more about my set
forget strategy and how it allows new
traders to generate anywhere from ,000
to $1,500 a week using my C fra strategy
just hit the link in the description
below I have a video where it explains
my philosophy completely and I
personally believe there is no other
strategy like this out there in the
market it has been tested for 6 years
and there's many results like these and
I have many success stories that Traders
within the first three months are
generating anywhere from $1,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader so if you guys want to see
more about that just hit the link in the
description below I appreciate you guys
watching this video all the way to the
end hit that like And subscribe button
and I'll see you guys in the next video